dealchecker.co.uk 2018-09-07

# Privacy

## Privacy Policy

DMC Digital is a UK registered company that wholly owns and operates the website dealchecker.co.uk. DMC Digital Ltd is part of the Webedia Group. This privacy policy refers to your use of the dealchecker website and the information that we may collect from you as you do so.

dealchecker.co.uk act as a data controller over the information that we collect from you as you use the site, meaning that we are responsible for looking after it. Later on we will refer to data processors. These are businesses that we use to help us to fulfil our promise to you.

The dealchecker website has been designed for use by those aged over 18 years old. Those under 18 should seek permission from a parent or guardian before using.

**Privacy policy updated: 24th May 2018**

### Why Do We Collect Data on Our Users?

As our users move through the site we track information on searches made, links clicked and the duration of time spent on each page. This information is collated and then used to help us to improve the user experience. It is through this data collection that we create filters that make navigating the site simple, build pages that feel intuitive to use and understand what it is that our users love. 

We also share anonymised data with our partners to help them to serve more relevant adverts to you.

For the information that we hold on our email users, please check out our [email privacy policy](https://www.dealchecker.co.uk/site/email-privacy.html).

### What Data Do We Collect

We collect information about the devices that our users utilise to view our site. We collect information about our users? IP address, operating system, screen resolution and referring website. 

Alongside this, we collect information about the actions that our users take on our website. We store data on clicks, user journeys and the duration of time spent on each page. 

We use Google Analytics and Adobe Analytics to collect data on the demographics of our users. This data is anonymised and not personally identifiable. It helps us to understand our audience and how it breaks down by age, gender and interests. You can opt out of this kind of data being collected using the cookie pop ups available on each page or via on our cookie page.

### How Long Do We Store Your Data For?

The length of time that data is stored for varies between the types of cookie. You can find more information on this over on our [cookie policy](https://www.dealchecker.co.uk/site/cookies.html).

For information on the length of time that email data is used, head on over to our [ email privacy policy.](https://www.dealchecker.co.uk/site/email-privacy.html)

### Who Do We Share Your Data With?

Here at dealchecker, we work with a number of partners to improve the experience that we can provide you (our users) with. These partners act as data processors, enabling us to run our website smoothly. 

#### Adobe

We use Adobe's analytics suite so that we can understand how our website is performing. We share our site usage data with them and they let us organise it into a manner that can be understood and used to make improvements. You can find out more about their GDPR plans [here](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/general-data-protection-regulation.html).

#### Google Analytics

Google Analytics also provides site usage data. In addition to this, it helps us to understand the demographic of our users so that we can provide content and deals that are relevant to them. Google uses a variety of methods to gather this data, for example when you sign up with a Google account, or also by some educated guesses based on your browsing history. They also enable us to recognise trends in page's popularity which stops us from becoming out of date.

#### Everycity

We work with [ Everycity](https://everycity.co.uk/) as a data processor to host our database. They allow us to store all of the great prices that we show on site, alongside a whole host of other information that ensures that dealchecker runs smoothly. 

### Cookies

dealchecker aims to be open and clear about the use of cookies on our website.

We use cookies to recognise users and devices using the dealchecker website. These cookies contain an anonymised email address.

If you do not have cookies enabled on your web browser you may find that some sections of dealchecker do not work as well as they should. For example our search tools rely on cookies to ensure we return users' individual search results.

dealchecker also uses cookies to analyse our users' behaviour on our site so that we can continue to improve the website experience.

Some cookies are permanently stored by your browser, whilst others are deleted as soon as you leave the site.

Our third parties use cookies to serve up adverts that are most relevant to you, but only store anonymised data in the cookies they use.

If you’d like to learn more click here to see our Cookie Policy which includes a complete list of all the cookies dealchecker uses. 

If you’re worried about cookies you can choose to clear your browser’s cookies history or even to disable cookies entirely - click here to learn how. Alternatively, you can control which cookies we store on you in the cookie pop ups which appear when you use our site or by clicking through here.

### Your Options

For those who subscribe to our email newsletters and use the site, the information that we store on how they use the website will be connected to their email address. These users can ask for their data to be deleted at any time by emailing [dataprotection@dealchecker.co.uk.](mailto:dataprotection@dealchecker.co.uk). Check out the [email privacy policy](https://www.dealchecker.co.uk/site/email-privacy.html) for further information. 

### Contact

For more information or if you have any questions for us, please do not hesitate to email us at [dataprotection@dealchecker.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@dealchecker.co.uk).

Alternatively, you can write to us at: DMC Digital Limited, 1st Floor, 2-4 Rufus Street, N1 6PE
